Finding Aid for Francis A. Kornegay Papers 1936-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Francis A. Kornegay Papers
1936-1977
1944-1977
Kornegay, Francis A.
Executive director of the Detroit Urban League, 1960-1978; general chronological files, topical files, correspondence, speeches, personal, Detroit Urban League materials, and other organizational activities files.
851651 Aa 2
18 linear feet
1 phonograph records
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Francis A. Kornegay (donor no. 4759 ). They came to the library in two principal accessions, in 1969 and 1977.
The collection is open for research.
Francis A. Kornegay was born in Mt. Olive, North Carolina in 1913. He attended and graduated from North Carolina College in Durham, North Carolina in 1935 with a B.A. degree in biology and mathematics. He received his M.A. degree in guidance and personnel from the University of Michigan in 1941. In 1944, he entered the Ph.D. program and in 1973, he received his doctorate. His thesis was entitled "A community survey of the inner city area of Detroit."
In 1944, he joined the staff of the Detroit Urban League as vocational secretary with the responsibility to convince business and industry to give African Americans a chance at better jobs. In 1947, he was named vocational services secretary with increased duties; and in 1950, his area was made a department within the Urban League and his title was changed to vocational services director. He was named assistant executive director in 1956 and executive director in 1960 replacing John C. Dancy. Kornegay retired in 1978.
In addition to his varied Urban League responsibilities, Kornegay was a member of various Detroit and Wayne County business and civic organizations. His organizational affiliations included the Detroit Commission on Community Relations, the Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company, Detroit TAAP (Total Action Against Poverty), among others.
The Kornegay papers are organized into seven series:
General Chronological File, 1944-1970 -- Boxes 1-4
Topical File, 1936-1968 -- Boxes 4-12
Correspondence, 1941-1975 -- Box 13
Speeches, 1940-1976 -- Box 13
Personal, 1960s-1970s -- Box 13
Urban League Materials, 1960-1973 -- Box 13-15
Organizational Affiliations, 1955-1975 -- Box 15-18
The papers of Francis A. Kornegay document four decades of service with the Detroit Urban League. These files which Kornegay categorized as personal and thus kept separate from the records of the Detroit Urban League which are also housed at the Bentley Library are a mixture of Urban League and non-Urban League related materials. The researcher interested in either Kornegay or the history of the Detroit Urban League during the Kornegay years (1944-1978) will need to examine both collections for relevant materials.
The Kornegay papers came to the library in two major accessions both of which required extensive processing. The two accessions were not interfiled, thus there are some files that might properly be placed elsewhere within the collection. The files received in 1977 (boxes 13-18) consisted primarily of materials which were generated after the initial papers were received and files which were active at the time of the initial deposit of material in 1969. The series received in 1969 were titled General Chronological and Topical Files. The materials received in 1977 were processed into five series: Correspondence, Speeches, Personal, Detroit Urban League, and Organizational Affiliations. On its surface, these appear to be six distinct series. On examination, however, there are some materials that could have been grouped together if the two accessions had been interfiled. The Correspondence series could have been interfiled with the General Chronological, for example; or the Detroit Urban League files to be found within the Topical Files series could have been placed with the Detroit Urban League series. The finding aid is small enough that the researcher should be able to locate similar files within the six series.
Subjects:
Afro-Americans.; Afro-Americans--Michigan.; Charities--Michigan--Detroit.; Civil rights--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.). Commission on Community Relations.; Detroit Urban League.; Education--Michigan--Detroit.; Labor--Michigan--Detroit.; Municipal government--Michigan--Detroit.; Social service--Michigan--Detroit.; Social service--Michigan--Detroit--Societies, etc.; Unemployed--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre/Form:
Sound recordings.
- General Chronological file, 1944-1970; 3.3 linear feet
  The General Chronological file (1944-1970; 3.3 linear ft.) is an artificially created series of correspondence and other papers arranged into a chronological sequence. The files pertain primarily to Kornegay's activities with the Urban League. The correspondence is largely of a personal nature, responding to requests and inquiries, accepting and offering congratulations, etc. Scattered throughout this series are reports of the vocational services department and speeches given by Kornegay.
  - Undated, 1944-April 1953; 29 folders (Box 1)
  - May 1953-1961, 31 folders (Box 2)
  - 1962-September 1966, 37 folders (Box 3)
  - October 1966-1970, 11 folders (Box 4)
- Topical files, 1936-1968; 8.5 linear feet
  Topical Files (1936-1968; 8.5 linear ft.) are further divided into three chronological sequence: 1936-1955, 1956-1960, and 1960-1968. In addition to subject files, these subseries include clippings, press releases, reports of the vocational services department, speeches, and other documents generated by the Detroit Urban League office. The subjects covered by the remainder of files relate to Kornegay's role as a spokesperson on behalf of Urban League programs and his involvement with Detroit area community organizations such as the Detroit Commission on Community Relations.
  - 1936-1955, mainly 1944-1955
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Convention, 1948 (Box 4)
    - American Red Cross, 1944-1945 (Box 4)
    - Apprenticeship, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
    - Back to School Campaigns, 1949-1955; 7 folders (Box 4)
    - Back to School Job Survey, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Baptist World Alliance Conference, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Brewery Industry
      - 1950 (Box 4)
      - 1955 (Box 4)
    - Carey, Archibald, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Chrysler Corporation, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Citizens Committee on the Fluoridation of Water, 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Discrimination Cases, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Employment, 1952-1954; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Employment of Negroes in City Departments, 1944; 1946-1947; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Employment of Negroes in County Departments, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Employment of Negroes in State Departments, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
    - European Contacts, 1952 (Box 4)
    - European Tour, 1952; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Home Federal Savings and Loan, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Housing Contacts, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
    - Industrial Associates, 1944-1945; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Industrial Relations Committee
      - 1945 (Box 5)
      - 1951, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - J.L. Hudson Company, 1947-1948 (Box 5)
    - James E. Shepard Memorial Foundation, 1949-1955 (Box 5)
    - Job Workship Conference, 1945 (Box 5)
    - Manual Revision, 1952-1956; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Meinzinger Art School, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Memoranda, 1951-1955 (Box 5)
    - Michigan Employment Security Commission Agreement, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - Milwaukee Regional Conference of Industrial Secretaries, 1945 (Box 5)
    - Moral Re-Armament, 1954 (Box 5)
    - Negro Research Data, 1944 (Box 5)
    - National Freedom Day Program phonograph record, February 1, 1951; 1 16" phonorecord 33 1/3 rpm (Box 5)
      (stored separately)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated; 1944-1955; 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Personal File
      - 1936-1943 (Box 5)
      - 1951 (Box 5)
    - Pilot Placement Project, 1948-1949 (Box 5)
    - Post Office, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Press Releases, undated; 1944-1954; 8 folders (Box 5)
    - Progress Reports, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Public Relations, 1954 (Box 5)
    - Reports of the Vocational Services Department, 1944-1955; 10 folders (Box 6)
    - Retail Stores Project, 1951-1952; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Shwayder Bros., Inc., 1947 (Box 6)
    - Social Work Course 229, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Social Workers' Club of Detroit, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
    - Speech material, 1955 (Box 6)
    - Speeches, 1951-1955 (Box 6)
    - Super Market Survey, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
    - Teamwork in Industry, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Tuskegee Trade Conference, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
    - United Community Services, 1953-1955 (Box 6)
    - Urban League of Gary, Indiana, 1955 (Box 6)
    - Vocational Opportunity Campaign
      - 1948-1950, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - 1952, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - 1955, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Vocational Services Advisory Committee, 1954-1955; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - White Collar Survey, 1948-1951 (Box 7)
  - 1956-1960
    - Alleged Discrimination in Employment, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
    - Annual Dinner, 1958-1960; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Bishop College, 1957-1958; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Boy Scout Project, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Camp McCoy, Wisconsin, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Central State College, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee on School Needs, 1957-1958; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Citizens for Schools, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Conference on Aging, 1956 (Box 7)
    - Congratulatory Letters, 1956-1960 (Box 7)
    - Detroit Commission on Children and Youth, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Detroit Public Schools, 1957-1960; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Detroit Urban League Guild, 1956-1957; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Detroit Urban League Inter-Agency Hi-Lites, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Equal Opportunity Day, 1958-1959; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - First Baptist Church, San Antonio, Texas, 1960 (Box 7)
    - General Motors, 1956-1958 (Box 7)
    - Green Pastures Camp, 1958-1959 (Box 7)
    - Manual Revision, 1956-1959 (Box 7)
    - Memoranda, 1956-1960; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Michigan Society for Mental Health, 1957-1960; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Monthly Reports of the Assistant Director, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
    - Morehouse College, 1957-1959 (Box 8)
    - Mother of the Year, 1958 (Box 8)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1957-1960 (Box 8)
    - North Carolina College, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Parker, Louise, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
    - Second Baptist Church, 1956-1960 (Box 8)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1958 (Box 8)
    - Speech material, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Speeches, 1956-1960; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Staff Recruitment, 1956-1957 (Box 8)
    - United Community Services, 1956-1960; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - 1960-1968
    - Active Community Teams, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 8)
    - Administrative and Clerical Council, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Agency for International Development, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Appointments, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Automobile Industry Survey, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Big Boy Restaurants, 1967 (Box 8)
    - Biographical material on FAK (Box 8)
    - Biographical Sketches of individuals within the Urban League and African-American community (Box 8)
    - Board of Education, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Brown, Raymond, 1964-1965 (Box 8)
    - Butzel-Stevens Scholarship Fund, 1961-1964; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Career Guide (Box 8)
    - Cass Apprentice School, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Central High School, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Charles H. Mahoney Memorial, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Baptist Institute, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
    - Chicago Urban League, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee for Economic Opportunity, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Citizens Committee for Equal Opportunity, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Civil Rights Act, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Class on Community Organizations, 1947; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Clerical Staff Meeting Minutes, 1961-1966 (Box 9)
    - Community Services Department, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
    - Complaints, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Con-Con Delegation, 1961 (Box 9)
    - Conference of Michigan Leagues-Workshop Session materials (Box 9)
    - Conference on Christian Laymen in Urban Structures, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Conference on Family Planning, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Counselors' Tea, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Crime Institute, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Commission on Community Relations, 1960-1967; 12 folders (Box 9)
    - Detroit Department of Health, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Detroit High School Study Commission, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Urban League
      - Agency Operations, 1966 (Box 9)
      - Career Conference, 1966 (Box 9)
      - Department Directors Meetings, 1960-1963 (Box 9)
      - Inter-Agency Hi-Lites, 1960-1967; 5 folders (Box 9)
      - Job Descriptions, 1966 (Box 9)
      - Northwest Branch, 1962 (Box 10)
      - Press Releases, 1960-1969; 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Program Developments, 1962-1964 (Box 10)
      - Program Prospectus, 1962-1965; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Reconstruction Fund, 1967 (Box 10)
      - Reports, 1965 (Box 10)
      - Requests for Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
      - Staff Meetings, 1960-1968; 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Story (Box 10)
      - Suggestions and Programs, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Detroit-Windsor International Freedom Festival, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Discrimination in Detroit Hospitals, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Empire State Federation of Woments Clubs, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Employment Agency Permits, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
    - Employment in Small Businesses, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Employment Problems of Working Women, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Equal Opportunity Day, 1962-1964; 4 folders (Box 10)
    - Executive Directors Seminar, 1966; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Family Planning, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Food Consumer Survey, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Forum for Detroit Area Metropolitan Goals, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
    - General Information, 1963-1966; 3 folders (Box 10)
    - General Motors, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Great Cities Project, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Guidance Association of Metropolitan Detroit, 1962-1963; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Home-Coming, 1966 (Box 10)
    - House Bills, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Industrial Relations-Vocational Guidance Council, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Jewish Community Council, 1961-1963 (Box 10)
    - Job Development and Employment Committee, 1964) (Box 10)
    - Job Order Records, 1963 (Box 10)
    - John C. Dancy Recognition Dinner, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Julian P. Rodgers Memorial, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Kalamazoo College, 1965 (Box 10)
    - Keep Michigan Beautiful, Inc., 1967 (Box 10)
    - Kettering High School, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Law Enforcement, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Library on Negro Life and History, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda-Administrative, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda-Administrative, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda-Staff Changes, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Metropolitan Detroit Conference on Religion and Race, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Catholic Conference, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Society for Mental Health, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Volunteer Leadership Avard, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Week, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Michigan Welfare League, 1961-1968; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Michigan White House Conference Follow-Up Committee, 1961 (Box 11)
    - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials, 1965; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - National Commission for Social Work Careers, 1967 (Box 11)
    - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, 1965 (Box 11)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare, 1965; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare, 1968 (Box 11)
    - National Urban League Field visit, 1962 (Box 11)
    - Neighborhood Youth Corps, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
    - North Carolina College, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
    - Open Occupancy (Box 11)
    - Outside Engagements, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Parents Seminar Project, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Past Presidents Tea, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Personnel Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
    - Personnel Matters, 1965-1966 (Box 11)
    - Police-Community Relations, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Poverty Program, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Project Upward Bound, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Radio Talks, 1968-1969 (Box 11)
    - Religious Resources, 1960-1966 (Box 11)
    - Revision of Policy Statement, 1965 (Box 11)
    - River Rouge High School-Commencement Address, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Robertson, Alvin C., 1964 (Box 11)
    - Roelofs Fund, 1962-1965; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - School Administrators Conference, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Senate Bill No. 165 (Box 11)
    - Skills Bank, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Skills Center, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Speech Material, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Speeches, undated; 1961-1969; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Staff Evaluations, 1965-1966 (Box 12)
    - Television Appearance, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Total Action Against Poverty, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - Treasury Department Address, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Tutorial Project with Mercy College, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - U.A.W.-C.I.O., 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - United Church Men, 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - United Community Services, 1964-1967 (Box 12)
    - United Foundation, 1961-1966; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - University of Detroit Lecture, 1965 (Box 12)
    - University of Michigan, 1965-1967 (Box 12)
    - Urban League Executives, 1961 (Box 12)
    - U.S.O. Board of Directors, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
    - Virginia Union University, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
    - War on Poverty, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Washington Bureau-National Urban League (Box 12)
    - Washington Conference, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Washington Staff Development Conference (Box 12)
    - Wayne County Community College, 1965 (Box 12)
    - White House Conference, 1966; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Wolverine State Missionary Baptist Layments Department, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
    - Workshop on the City Church, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Youth Conference, 1964 (Box 12)
- Correspondence, 1941-1975; 0.4 linear feet
  Correspondence (1941-1975; 0.4 linear ft.) is the series that largely overlaps and continues the General Chronological file sequence. One of the files in this series concerns the Urban League's position on civil rights demonstrations.
  - Undated, 1941-1975; 18 folders (Box 13)
  - Re public affairs, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Re Urban League position on civil rights demonstrations (Box 13)
- Speeches, 1940-1976; 0.3 linear feet
  Speeches (1940-1976; 0.3 linear ft.) includes final copies with some drafts of speeches given by Francis Kornegay primarily in the 1960s and 1970s.
  - Undated, 1940-1976; 9 folders (Box 13)
  - Rough drafts (Box 13)
  - Speech material (Box 13)
- Personal, 1960s-1970s; 0.3 linear feet
  Personal (1960s-1970s; 0.3 linear ft.) is a small series consisting of some of Kornegay's publications and files pertaining to his doctoral dissertation.
  - Kornegay doctoral dissertation material, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Kornegay publications, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous personal items (Box 13)
- Urban League materials, 1960-1973; 2 linear feet
  Urban League Materials (1960-1973; 2 linear ft.) consists of documents and reports generated by the Detroit Urban League and accumulated items sent to the Detroit chapter by the national office and by other area chapters.
  - Detroit Urban League
    - History (Box 13)
    - Reports
      - (annual), 1968 (Box 13)
      - (annual), 1969 (Box 14)
      - (community services), 1969 (Box 14)
      - (educational services), 1969 (Box 14)
      - (annual), 1970-1973 (Box 14)
    - New Thrust Program, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Committee Structure (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Minutes (Box 14)
    - Proposals, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Memos, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Library (Box 14)
    - Staff Schedules (Box 14)
    - Statements and Press Releases and Publications (Box 14)
    - Newsletter (Box 14)
    - Research material, 7 folders (Box 14)
    - Reference material, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Special Projects
      - Absenteeism (Box 14)
      - ADC (Box 14)
      - Education and Youth Incentive (Box 14)
      - Employment (Box 15)
      - Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner (Box 15)
      - Goal Setting (Box 15)
      - Hypertension (Box 15)
      - Minorities in Media (Box 15)
      - Radio Notes, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Sickle Cell Anemia (Box 15)
      - Veterans (Box 15)
  - Other Urban League Organizations
    - Michigan Council of Urban League Executives, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Chicago Urban League (Box 15)
    - St. Louis Urban League (Box 15)
    - Urban Leagues in New York State (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Urban Leagues (Box 15)
  - National Urban League
    - 1960 (Box 15)
    - 1962 (Box 15)
    - 1964 (Box 15)
    - 1966, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Human Resources Program (Box 15)
    - Religious Resources Program, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Memos (Box 15)
    - Newsletters (Box 15)
    - Whitney Young, Jr., 3 folders (Box 15)
- Organizational Affiliations, 1955-1975; 3.2 linear feet
  Organizational Affiliations (1955-1975; 3.2 linear ft.) is divided into three subseries: Baptist Material, Detroit - Total Action Against Poverty Committee (TAAP), and Other Organizations.
  - Baptist material
    - Fund of Renewal, 1975-1976; 6 folders (Box 15)
    - Fund of Renewal printed material (Box 15)
    - American Baptist Church, Statements of Concern, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Baptist World Alliance, 1955 (Box 16)
    - Wolverine State Missionary Conference, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Detroit-Total Action Against Poverty Committee (TAAP)
    - TAAP-Policy Advisory Committee, 1963-1969; 14 folders (Box 16)
    - Citizens Participation Sub-Committee (Box 16)
    - TAAP Health Sub-committee
      - General, 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Greater Detroit Area Hospital Council (Box 16)
      - Burton Mercy Hospital, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Detroit Medical Center (Box 17)
      - Plymouth General Hospital (Box 17)
      - Southwest General Hospital (Box 17)
      - Health Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Proposed programs, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Education Programs (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Employment programs (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Manpower Development Training Act, 1964-1968; 5 folders (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Personnel Sub-Committee (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Funding (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Legal Services and Credit Unions (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Vista Programs (Box 17)
    - TAAP-Miscellaneous programs (Box 17)
  - Other Organizations
    - Detroit Police, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Detroit Public Library, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Detroit and Wayne County Governmental Units (Box 17)
    - Detroit-1967 Riot, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 17)
    - Equal Opportunity Commission, 1963-1966; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Florida Memorial College, 1964-1971; 7 folders (Box 18)
    - Franklin Settlement (Detroit) Annual Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 18)
    - Golden State Insurance, 1961-1975; 13 folders (Box 18)
    - Habari (Box 18)
    - Mental Health and Criminal Justice (Box 18)
    - Michigan Civil Rights Commission
      - 1964-1970, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Conference on Civil Rights, April 1966 (Box 18)
    - Michigan Commission on Crime
      - Crime Survey (Box 18)
      - Crime Reports (Box 18)
    - Michigan Fair Practices Commission (Box 18)
    - Minority Agency Executives, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - Minority Business Opportunity Committee (Box 18)
    - National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials (Box 18)
    - United Community Services (Box 18)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 18)
    - Virginia Union University (Box 18)